https://www.metcalfemodels.com/privacy/

Contact Us
OUR LAST POSTING DATES FOR CHRISTMAS ARE - UK TUESDAY 22ND DECEMBER, ALL ORDERS OUTSIDE OF THE UK THURSDAY 3RD DECEMBER. THANK YOU FOR YOUR UNDERSTANDING.
Privacy
Home / Privacy
Information Collection & Use
This notice describes the privacy policy of Metcalfe Models (Metcalfe Models & Toys Ltd). By visiting our website www.metcalfemodels.com you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Notice.
General Privacy: If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement or any requests concerning your personal data then please e-mail us at info@metcalfemodels.com By sharing your personal information with us, and by continuing to use our website, you confirm that you have read and understood the terms of this privacy policy. We take responsibility for the personal information we collect about you, and we aim to be transparent about how we handle it, and give you control over it.
The information we gather from you the “Customer” will help us develop your experience with Metcalfe Models. We use the information to handle orders, deliver products and process payments, communicate with you about orders, products, and promotional offers, update our records and generally maintain your account with us. We also use this information to improve our website and enable third parties to carry out technical functions on behalf of Metcalfe Models.
Metcalfe Models may collect personal information which we receive when you use our website or when you contact us. This may include information which you provide where you complete one of our forms, enter information on the Metcalfe Models website or contact Metcalfe Models directly in writing or by phone. We may collect the following types of information, Your name, Address, E-mail Address and Telephone number.
If you contact Metcalfe Models requiring a Trade account then the following information will be required, Company Name, Company address, Owners / Directors name(s), E-mail, Telephone number(s), Vat number, Company registration Number, Bank Details.
Email Communications
As a user of our products, we will need to send you support communications by e-mail such as transaction messaging and delivery schedules.
Our Use of Cookies
Please note that we use cookies on the Website. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. For example, the user will not be able to participate in any of our Contests, etc that may periodically take place. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.
Log Files
We use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
Scroll horizontally for more information
Cookie Owner
Cookie Name
Cookie Description
Amazon Web Services
AWSLEB
This cookie stores information about which part of our server farm was used by your most recent visit. This allows us to optimise our site, and your experience for various performance and server management reasons.
Mail Chimp
PHPSESSID
This cookie is strictly necessary to provide you with services available through our websites and to use some of its features, such as access to secure areas.
Google Analytics
_ga
Google Analytics gathers information allowing us to understand interactions with our websites and ultimately refine that experience to better serve you.
Google Analytics
_gat
Google Analytics gathers information allowing us to understand interactions with our websites and ultimately refine that experience to better serve you.
Google Analytics
_gid
This cookie name is asssociated with Google Universal Analytics. This appears to be a new cookie and as of Spring 2017 no information is available from Google. It appears to store and update a unique value for each page visited.
WordPress
wfvt_
This allows a security plugin we use to operate
WordPress
wfwaf-authcookie
This cookie is set by the WordPress security plugin “Wordfence”. It is used to authenticate user’s login request.
Woocommerce
woocommerce_cart_hash
This cookie contains information about the cart as a whole and helps WooCommerce know when the cart data changes.
Woocommerce
woocommerce_items_in_cart
This cookie contains information about the cart as a whole and helps WooCommerce know when the cart data changes.
Wordfence
wordfence_verifiedHuman
This Wordfence cookie is a Wordfence security plug-in used to protect the Site against malicious attacks.
WordPress
wordpress_logged_in
After login, wordpress sets the wordpress_logged_in_[hash] cookie, which indicates when you’re logged in, and who you are, for most interface use.
WordPress
wordpress_sec
Essential WordPress session management cookies for logged in users.
WordPress
wordpress_test_cookie
WordPress sets this cookie when you navigate to the login page. The cookie is used to check whether your web browser is set to allow, or reject cookies.
WordPress
wp-setting-
WordPress also sets a few wp-settings-[UID] cookies. The number on the end is your individual user ID from the users database table. This is used to customize your view of admin interface, and possibly also the main site interface.
WordPress
wp-settings-time-
WordPress also sets a few wp-settings-{time}-[UID] cookies. The number on the end is your individual user ID from the users database table. This is used to customize your view of admin interface, and possibly also the main site interface.
gdpr_popup
Metcalfe Models
This cookie is used to track who has already been shown the notice. The cookie has been set never to expire unless there is a change in the privacy policy.
Woocommerce
wp_woocommerce_session_
This cookie (wp_woocommerce_session_) contains a unique code for each customer so that it knows where to find the cart data in the database for each customer. No personal information is stored within these cookies.
Third parties who provide services on our behalf
We share your personal information with certain third parties who provide services on our behalf. They only have access to the personal information they need to perform those services. They are required to keep your personal information confidential and may not use it other than as we ask them to and always in accordance with this privacy policy.
The third parties who provide services on our behalf fall into the following categories: Those helping us to deliver products to you such as a courier or the Royal Mail. Third parties that assist us with our marketing, helping us to understand how well our advertising works, to reach people who are more interested in Metcalfe Models products, by setting cookies on our websites (more information on this can be found in our cookies policy.) Third party Marketing company (s) who monitor and post to our Social Media platforms on behalf of Metcalfe Models.
Social Media
You may use social media to contact us about your Metcalfe Models products, or to let people know what you think about our products. The information we collect from social media and online sites sometimes includes personal information that has been put online and is publicly available. We make sure any information we use is properly credited to its source or is made anonymous.
These online and social media sites may have their own privacy policies explaining how they use and share your personal information. You should carefully review those privacy policies before you use these sites to make sure that you are happy with how your personal information is being collected and shared.
Newsletter
All customers can sign up to the Metcalfe Models newsletter on the website www.metcalfemodels.com, the information required is Name, and E-mail address. The Newsletter is used to announce the launch of new products, changes made to important information such as updating the privacy policy, changes in opening times throughout the year such as the Christmas period. You can unsubscribe to such information at any time by selecting the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the newsletter, or by contacting Metcalfe Models directly via e-mail – info@metcalfemodels.com.
How long we keep personal information
Metcalfe Models will only retain customers’ personal information for as long as it needs it to carry out a purpose or meet a particular obligation.
Keeping personal information accurate
Metcalfe Models will ensure that personal information is kept accurate and up to date as far as is reasonably possible. However, Metcalfe Models relies on customers to ensure that some of the information it holds about them is accurate and up-to-date. We encourage customers to inform us of any changes to their information (e.g. by updating your address details on our website), they can do this by logging into the account or by contacting us by e-mail info@metcalfemodels.com
Access to your personal information
We give you control over the personal information we collect about you, to ensure it is accurate and reflects your preferences.
You have the right to access, update and amend personal information that we hold about you. In certain circumstances, you can also:
object to our use of your personal information for certain purposes;
ask us to restrict our use of your personal information;
ask us to remove or delete personal information about you; or
provide your personal information to a third-party provider of services.
If you would like to exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal information, please e-mail us at info@metcalfemodels.com
How we protect personal data
We know how important it is to protect and manage your personal data. This section sets out some of the measures we have in place.
We use computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption, and we enforce physical access controls to our buildings and files to keep this data safe. We only authorise access to employees who need it to carry out their job responsibilities.
Our procedures mean that we may request proof of identity before we share your personal information with you.
In the unlikely event that we do suffer a security breach which compromises our protection of your personal information and we need to let you know about it, we will do so.
However, whilst we take appropriate technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal data, please note that we cannot guarantee the security of any personal data that you transfer over the internet to us.
Contact Us
If you have any questions, comments or concerns, or would like to make a complaint about how we use the personal information we hold about you, please email us at info@metcalfemodels.com
We will keep our privacy policy under regular review and will place any updates on this webpage. This privacy policy was last updated May 2018.
Sign up here to receive updates on our range and new product releases
Please tick to confirm you are happy to receive emails from Metcalfe Models Please tick to confirm you are happy to receive emails from Metcalfe Models
Unbeatable quality
Quick dispatch on all orders
Friendly Technical Support Available!
what are you looking for?
ADDED TO YOUR WISHLIST
Keep Browsing
View Full Wishlist
We use cookies on this website, by continuing to browse the site you are agreeing to our use of cookies.
Find out more.
